<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Trading Economics Summary</title>
    <link>https://tradingeconomics.com</link>
    <description>Hourly snapshot of Trading Economics homepage tiles</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:19:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>TASI Falls 5% at the Open</title>
      <description>Saudi Arabia’s benchmark stock index, TASI, fell by as much as 5% to 10,214 at Sunday’s open, its lowest level since March 2023, before recovering to around 10,700 as investors assessed the implications of U.S. and Israeli strikes on Iran. In retaliation to attack, Iran moved to restrict traffic through the strategic Strait of Hormuz, a critical transit route for roughly one-fifth of global oil supply and significant volumes of natural gas, and launched attacks across neighbouring states, including Saudi Arabia. While escalating tensions in the Middle East are likely to disrupt regional economic activity and weigh on investor sentiment, oil prices are expected to surge. Higher crude prices could provide support to Saudi Arabia’s economy, given its position as one of the world’s leading oil exporters.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold Set for a Sharp Advance</title>
      <description>Gold prices are poised to surge when trading resumes Sunday night, driven by renewed safe-haven demand after US and Israel's attacks on Iran sharply escalated tensions in the Middle East. In retaliation, Iran moved to restrict traffic through the strategic Strait of Hormuz, a vital route for about one-fifth of the world’s oil and substantial natural gas flows, and launched attacks across neighbouring states, including the United Arab Emirates, Bahrain, Kuwait, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Jordan, Iraq and Syria. Bullion had already been on the rise, trading at 1-month highs of $5,278 on Friday and approching an all time high of $5,500 hit at the end of January as investors anticipated and attack and weighed aggressive US trade policies against persistently elevated inflation data.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea Export Growth Beats Estimates</title>
      <description>South Korea’s exports jumped 29.0% yoy in February 2026 to a record USD 67.45 billion for the month, beating market forecasts of 24% but easing from January’s 33.8% surge due to three fewer working days amid the Lunar New Year break, preliminary data showed. Still, shipments rose for a ninth straight month. Semiconductor sales soared 160.9% to a fresh high of USD 25.16 billion, topping USD 20 billion for a third month in a row, fueled by strong AI investment and rising memory chip prices. Exports also grew for computers (222%), ships (41%), and wireless communications (13%); but fell for autos (-20.8%), petrochemicals (-15.4%), and steel (-7.8%). Shipments expanded to the U.S. (30%), China (34%), the ASEAN countries (30.4%), and the EU (10.3%). Meanwhile, Seoul has launched a strategy to lift exports to a new record USD 740 billion this year, from a top USD 709.7 billion in 2025, by diversifying products and markets and strengthening financial support.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Stocks Close the Week in the Red</title>
      <description>The S&amp;P 500 lost 0.4%, the Nasdaq lost 0.4%, and the Dow Jones tumbled 1.1% as a hot inflation report and a tech sector retreat pulled the major benchmarks into the red for February on Friday. These hotter-than-expected figures suggested companies are passing tariff costs to consumers and complicating the path for Federal Reserve rate cuts. Sentiment was further damaged by massive layoffs at Block and disappointing guidance from CoreWeave which sank 18.6%. Nvidia extended its slide with a 4.1% drop as skepticism grew regarding the sustainability of AI capital expenditures by major tech firms. While Dell surged 21.8% on record AI server demand and a massive buyback plan, financial heavyweights like Apollo and Jefferies fell 8.6% to 9.3% on private credit contagion fears. Despite the volatility, February saw record corporate buyback authorizations of 233.3 billion dollars providing a floor for some large cap names.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Producer Prices Rise More Than Expected</title>
      <description>US producer prices increased 0.5% mom in January 2026, following a downwardly revised 0.4% rise in December and above forecasts of 0.3%. Prices of services increased 0.8%, the most since July, led by a 14.4% jump in margins for professional and commercial equipment wholesaling. Prices also increased for apparel, footwear; chemicals; bundled wired telecommunications access services; health, beauty, and optical goods retailing; and food and alcohol retailing. On the other hand, prices for goods were down 0.3%, the largest fall since March 2025, mainly due to a 5.5% drop in gasoline. Prices for chicken eggs, electric power, gas fuels, fresh fruits and melons, and ethanol also moved lower. Year-on-year, producer prices went up 2.9%, the least in three months, but above forecasts of 2.6%. Core producer prices jumped 0.8%, also the most in six months, compared to forecasts of 0.3%. Year-on-year, core producer prices rose 3.6%, well above forecasts of 3%.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany Inflation Slows to 1.9% in February</title>
      <description>Germany’s annual inflation rate eased to 1.9% in February 2026 from 2.1% in January, coming in slightly below market expectations of 2.0%, according to preliminary estimates. The harmonized index of consumer prices, closely monitored by the ECB, also edged down to 2.0% from 2.1%, leaving both measures broadly aligned with the central bank’s 2% target. Goods inflation slowed to 0.8% from 1.0%, as energy prices declined at a faster pace (-1.9% vs. -1.7%) and food inflation cooled markedly to 1.1% from 2.1%. Services inflation held steady at 3.2%, while core inflation, which excludes food and energy, remained unchanged at 2.5%.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
